<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<changelog project="GM.XrmToolBox.UserRoleMatrix" semver="true">

	<unreleased>
		<added />
		<changed />
		<fixed />
		<removed />
	</unreleased>

	<release version="1.0.0.0" date="2026-01-20">
		<added>
			<item>Load users from Dataverse (systemuser)</item>
			<item>Load direct user roles (systemuserroles)</item>
			<item>Load roles via Owner Teams (teammembership + teamroles)</item>
			<item>Grid with User/Email/User BU, Role/Role BU, Team/Team BU, Assignment Type</item>
			<item>Duplicate detection (same role direct + team) with column "Duplicate"</item>
			<item>Search box (client-side filtering)</item>
			<item>Dropdown filters: Business Unit, Team, Assignment Type (All/Direct/Team)</item>
			<item>Export: CSV</item>
			<item>Export: Excel (.xlsx)</item>
		</added>
	</release>
	<release version="2.0.0.0" date="2026-01-23">
		<added>
			<item>Optimizations</item>
			<item>Bugfixes</item>
		</added>
	</release>
	<release version="4.0.0.0" date="2026-01-24">
		<added>
			<item>Optimizations</item>
			<item>Bugfixes</item>
		</added>
	</release>
	<release version="5.0.0.2" date="2026-01-25">
		<fixed>
			<item>Add User Role failed for users outside the root Business Unit when Modern Business Unit (EnableOwnershipAcrossBusinessUnits) was disabled. The role is now assigned using the user's own Business Unit instead of the root BU.</item>
		</fixed>
	</release>
	<release version="5.0.0.3" date="2026-02-25">
		<added>
			<item>Views dropdown (System Views and Personal Views) for both Users and Owner Teams, with per-entity view persistence.</item>
			<item>Delete selected role assignments (direct user-role disassociation).</item>
			<item>Add User Role dialog with dynamic role loading per Business Unit.</item>
			<item>EnableOwnershipAcrossBusinessUnits org setting detection displayed in the status bar.</item>
			<item>View-based filtering: load only records matching the selected Dataverse view (FetchXml).</item>
		</added>
		<changed>
			<item>Toolbar reorganized into two levels: actions on Level 1, filters (View, Business Unit, Assignment, Search) on Level 2.</item>
			<item>About icon moved to the far right of the toolbar.</item>
		</changed>
		<fixed>
			<item>Add User Role now uses the selected user's own Business Unit when Modern Business Unit is disabled, preventing errors for non-root BU users.</item>
		</fixed>
	</release>
	<release version="5.0.1.0" date="2026-03-12">
		<fixed>
			<item>Compatibility issue fixed</item>
		</fixed>
	</release>
	<release version="5.0.1.1" date="2026-03-13">
		<added>
			<item>Team Business Unit filter dropdown on the filters toolbar (Level 2), next to the Assignment filter.</item>
			<item>Role Business Unit filter dropdown on the filters toolbar (Level 2), to filter rows by Role Business Unit.</item>
			<item>Add User to Owner Team" button: opens a dialog to add a user to an Owner Team (AddMembersTeamRequest).</item>
		</added>
		<changed>
			<item>Delete button now handles team-inherited role records: shows a confirmation popup warning that removing a user from an Owner Team will remove all roles inherited from that team, with OK/Cancel options.</item>
		</changed>
	</release>
</changelog>

